<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>education on Mohit Khodidas</title>
    <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in education on Mohit Khodidas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2019, Steve Francia and Mohit Patel; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Does it Mean to be a Teacher?</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/what_does_it_mean_to_be_a_teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/what_does_it_mean_to_be_a_teacher/</guid>
      <description>Happy Teachers&amp;rsquo; Day to all teachers.
Hermann Hesse said, &amp;ldquo;Teachers are more essential than anything else, men and women who can give the young the ability to judge and distinguish, who serve them as examples of the honouring of truth, obedience to the things of the spirit&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
Teachers and administrators (us) are essentially humans. We are people before we are teachers. And the failings and travails of being human cannot be discarded in the process of becoming a teacher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Higher Education and Rankings</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/indian_higher_education_and_rankings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/indian_higher_education_and_rankings/</guid>
      <description>/Posted originally at projectnoesis.in on [2021-03-08]/
Let&amp;rsquo;s acknowledge the problem, so we can get working
A couple of years ago I wrote in a dejected Facebook post that I spend more of my time in authority appeasement then on creative work. While I have learned to refrain from making caustic remarks, what remains true is that the fundamental nature of relationship between private Higher Education Institutions (HEIs) and departments is one of distrust and whataboutery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranks and Rankers</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/ranks_and_rankers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/ranks_and_rankers/</guid>
      <description>In all matters of taste and rankings and classifications that we inadvertently take part in our daily lives, I go back to Bourdieu and his thoughts on distinction:
Taste classifies, and it classifies the classifier. Social subjects, classified by their classifications, distinguish themselves by the distinctions they make, between the beautiful and the ugly, the distinguished and the vulgar, in which their position in the objective classifications is expressed or betrayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Teachers&#39; Day</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/happy_teachers_day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/happy_teachers_day/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this sometime back. Resharing on the occasion of Teachers&amp;rsquo; Day in India.
What, then, is truth? A mobile army of metaphors, metonyms, and anthropomorphisms – in short, a sum of human relations, which have been enhanced, transposed, and embellished poetically and rhetorically, and which after long use seem firm, canonical, and obligatory to a people: truths are illusions about which one has forgotten that this is what they are; metaphors which are worn out and without sensuous power; coins which have lost their pictures and now matter only as metal, no longer as coins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes on Education</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/quotes_on_education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/quotes_on_education/</guid>
      <description>Richard Rorty Rorty presents knowledge, not as a representation of the real world or a “match” between knowledge and reality, but rather as a collection of conceptual structures that are adapted, or viable, within a person&amp;rsquo;s range of experience. In other words, the person&amp;rsquo;s knowledge “fits” with the world, much like how a key fits a lock (Bodner, 1986). Each of us builds our own key by making sense of the world, and many different keys can open a given lock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Schools</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_schools/</guid>
      <description>What, then, is truth? A mobile army of metaphors, metonyms, and anthropomorphisms – in short, a sum of human relations, which have been enhanced, transposed, and embellished poetically and rhetorically, and which after long use seem firm, canonical, and obligatory to a people: truths are illusions about which one has forgotten that this is what they are; metaphors which are worn out and without sensuous power; coins which have lost their pictures and now matter only as metal, no longer as coins.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
