<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ragasvara on Mohit Khodidas</title>
    <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/ragasvara/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ragasvara on Mohit Khodidas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2019, Steve Francia and Mohit Patel; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/ragasvara/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Birds of Raga Svara</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/birds-of-ragasvara/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/birds-of-ragasvara/</guid>
      <description>Green Bee-eater I spotted this Green Bee-eater today morning. It is fairly common to see in rural areas. Bee-eaters eat insects, especially bees, wasps and ants. This is the first time I have managed to photograph one with a bee in its mouth.
Green Bree-Eater with a bee in its beak.
Green Bee-Eater at Raga Svara
Coppersmith Barbet The coppersmith barbet (Psilopogon haemacephalus), also called crimson-breasted barbet and coppersmith, is an Asian barbet with crimson forehead and throat, known for its metronomic call that sounds similar to a coppersmith striking metal with a hammer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birds of Raga Svara</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/birds-of-ragasvara/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/birds-of-ragasvara/</guid>
      <description>Green Bee-eater I spotted this Green Bee-eater today morning. It is fairly common to see in rural areas. Bee-eaters eat insects, especially bees, wasps and ants. This is the first time I have managed to photograph one with a bee in its mouth.
Green Bree-Eater with a bee in its beak.
Green Bee-Eater at Raga Svara
Coppersmith Barbet The coppersmith barbet (Psilopogon haemacephalus), also called crimson-breasted barbet and coppersmith, is an Asian barbet with crimson forehead and throat, known for its metronomic call that sounds similar to a coppersmith striking metal with a hammer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanctuary at Raga</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/sanctuary-at-raga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/sanctuary-at-raga/</guid>
      <description>Raga is a sanctuary amidst swathes of dry, arid expanse. It is incredible, almost magical, to see what a small parcel of land, taken care of, loved, can do for our ecology. The primary dwellers of Raga are the trees, plants, birds and animals. Our ecology is kind and strong, caring and wanton in equal measure.
In early winter mornings at Raga, I find a solace that is rare, nearly impossible to feel in the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanctuary at Raga</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/sanctuary-at-raga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/sanctuary-at-raga/</guid>
      <description>Raga is a sanctuary amidst swathes of dry, arid expanse. It is incredible, almost magical, to see what a small parcel of land, taken care of, loved, can do for our ecology. The primary dwellers of Raga are the trees, plants, birds and animals. Our ecology is kind and strong, caring and wanton in equal measure.
In early winter mornings at Raga, I find a solace that is rare, nearly impossible to feel in the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Hospitality</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/thoughts_on_hospitality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/thoughts_on_hospitality/</guid>
      <description>With Raga Svara, and with Northstar as well, but more acutely at Raga, I come to the question of étranger or xenos. I am unable to take on the role of a subservient host. Hospitality is an act of giving and receiving, a game if you will. The rules and codes must be adhered to. However, it always remains a struggle. It is never a transaction.
While all our services are priced, value truly remains outside of economic rationality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raga Svara Habitat Collective</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/habitat_collective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/habitat_collective/</guid>
      <description>Aristotle said something to the effect that nature has made all things specifically for the sake of man and that the value of non-human thing in nature is merely instrumental. This line of thinking troubles me. And, it continues till this day. The inherent drive for dominion of man over nature. It is not just Aristotle, although he seems to be foremost in a long line of similar thought. Genesis 1: 27–8 states: And God blessed them, and God said unto them, Be fruitful, and multiply, and replenish the earth, and subdue it: and have dominion over fish of the sea, and over fowl of the air, and over every living thing that moveth upon the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pause and Connect with Nature</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/pause_and_connect_with_nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/pause_and_connect_with_nature/</guid>
      <description>Raga - Nature
Pause and connect with nature. We are building a place where we can pause and connect with nature.
We have forgotten how to cooperate with nature. We are habituated to establishing our dominion in all aspects of life, including nature. Living in harmony with nature is long gone. We use her for our gains which comes at the cost of other rightful members of the habitat. We have forgotten to respond to the seasonal and temporal patterns of nature, much to our own physical and psychological detriment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
