<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ragasvara on Mohit Khodidas</title>
    <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/ragasvara/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ragasvara on Mohit Khodidas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/ragasvara/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Birds of Raga Svara</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/birds-of-ragasvara/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/birds-of-ragasvara/</guid>
      <description>Green Bee-eater I spotted this Green Bee-eater today morning. It is fairly common to see in rural areas. Bee-eaters eat insects, especially bees, wasps and ants. This is the first time I have managed to photograph one with a bee in its mouth.
Green Bree-Eater with a bee in its beak.
Green Bee-Eater at Raga Svara
Coppersmith Barbet The coppersmith barbet (Psilopogon haemacephalus), also called crimson-breasted barbet and coppersmith, is an Asian barbet with crimson forehead and throat, known for its metronomic call that sounds similar to a coppersmith striking metal with a hammer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanctuary at Raga</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/sanctuary-at-raga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/sanctuary-at-raga/</guid>
      <description>Raga is a sanctuary amidst swathes of dry, arid expanse. It is incredible, almost magical, to see what a small parcel of land, taken care of, loved, can do for our ecology. The primary dwellers of Raga are the trees, plants, birds and animals. Our ecology is kind and strong, caring and wanton in equal measure.
In early winter mornings at Raga, I find a solace that is rare, nearly impossible to feel in the city.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
