<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>literature on Mohit Khodidas</title>
    <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/literature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in literature on Mohit Khodidas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2019, Steve Francia and Mohit Patel; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/literature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dying of Our Dreaming</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/dying_of_dreaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/dying_of_dreaming/</guid>
      <description>What was it you haunted so far that we
must dream of it always, dying of our dreaming?
And of what other state do you speak so low
that we cannot remember it?
-George Seferis
This poem has haunted me for as long as I can remember. I never knew who Seferis was, until I read this line in a Gujarati book by Suresh Joshi. I have been burdened with this haunting, surreal image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folk Tales Project at Northstar</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/folktales_northstar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/folktales_northstar/</guid>
      <description>Northstar Folk Tales Project
I have started a small new project to bring Folk Tales (and fairy tales) from around the world to learners at Northstar, with a particular focus on tales from India. I have, since quite a long time, felt the need to tell and hear stories that feel rooted in our sensibilities, our culture. Our kids read and hear amazing stories from around the world, including the Grimm Brothers&amp;rsquo; stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>His Master&#39;s Voice - Stanislaw Lem</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/his_masters_voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/his_masters_voice/</guid>
      <description>One of the greatest of writers, for me, is Stanislaw Lem. I think that sci-fi has the most natural affinity to philosophical realm. Lem (and PKD and LeGuin) seamlessly travel between sci-fi and philosophy. I read Lem&amp;rsquo;s Solaris many years ago after watching Steven Soderbergh&amp;rsquo;s movie. I did not know of Andrei Tarkovsky&amp;rsquo;s masterpiece at the time. Later I watched that too. Solaris (the book) remains one of the greatest works on the unfathomable and mysterious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperion - Dan Simmons</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/hyperion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/hyperion/</guid>
      <description>Over the years I have developed a system of reading where I alternate between philosophy and science-fiction books. At almost any given time, I&amp;rsquo;d be reading either one. I find it extremely hard to find a science-fiction author who I enjoy, primarily in style of prose and sweep of concepts. Some of my favourites are Stanislaw Lem, Philip K. Dick, Ursula LeGuin and Alastair Reynolds. Over the last few months I must have tried at least 10 different authors, unable to connect with any.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Underground - Fyodor Dostoevsky</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/notes_from_underground/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/notes_from_underground/</guid>
      <description>Part 1 Jorge Luis Borges said:
Like the discovery of love, like the discovery of the sea, the discovery of Dostoevsky marks and important date in one&amp;rsquo;s life.
I discovered Fyodor Dostoevsky late in my life. It took me many attempts over some years to complete The Brothers Karamazov. It is impossible, for a mediocre thinker and writer like me, to even begin to describe the depth and contours of Dostoevsky&amp;rsquo;s writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I was Introduced to Borges</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/how_i_was_introduced_to_borges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/how_i_was_introduced_to_borges/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I wonder how I stumbled upon Borges. I remember one passage that shattered my mind. The opening paragraph of Michel Foucault&amp;rsquo;s The Order of Things had these lines:
This book first arose out of a passage in Borges, out of the laughter that shattered, as I read the passage, all the familiar landmarks of my thought - our thought, the thought that bears the stamp of our age and our geography - breaking up all the ordered surfaces and all the planes with which we are accustomed to tame the wild profusion of existing things, and continuing long afterwards to disturb and threaten with collapse our age-old distinction between the Same and the Other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Babylon Lottery</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/babylon_lottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/babylon_lottery/</guid>
      <description>This week I led a close reading of Jorge Luis Borges&amp;rsquo;s short story The Babylon Lottery. It is one of my favourite short stories.
Babylon Lottery</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning Roberto Bolaño</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/beginning_roberto_bolano/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/beginning_roberto_bolano/</guid>
      <description>The greatest writer of the 20th century, if not all time, for me, is Jorge Luis Borges. And if one reads Borges, he must also read Roberto Bolaño. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read Bolaño before and I am starting with 2666. A serendipitous start with this quote in the book&amp;rsquo;s opening:
An oasis of horror in a desert of boredom. -Charles Baudelaire
And Baudelaire reminds me that I must return to Fleurs du Mal soon again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ones Who Walk Away From Omelas</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/ones_who_walk_away_omelas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/ones_who_walk_away_omelas/</guid>
      <description>We will be reading a short story by Ursula Le Guin. She is one of the greatest Scifi writers (and one of my favourites). This short story, The Ones Who Walk Away From Omelas, presents a moral dilemma.
Ursula Le Guin shows a city; full of happy people; people without bondage and guilt; dancing in carnivals under bright, clear skies. Their perfect lives have just one condition: a single child tortured indefinitely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Method</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_method/</guid>
      <description>कबीरा कुआँ एक है,
पानी भरे अनेक
भांडे ही में भेद है,
पानी सब में एक
-Kabir
O Kabir, there is but one well
And many who draw
Difference is the vessel
Water stays the same.
(my poor translation)
Hermann Hesse, like Kabir, is one of those writers who can convey deep ideas with incredibly lucid writing. The Glass Bead Game is an exploration of many ideas. I was piqued by one on method.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
