<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Galleries on Mohit Khodidas</title>
    <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Galleries on Mohit Khodidas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2019, Steve Francia and Mohit Patel; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Birds of Raga Svara</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/birds-of-ragasvara/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/birds-of-ragasvara/</guid>
      <description>Green Bee-eater I spotted this Green Bee-eater today morning. It is fairly common to see in rural areas. Bee-eaters eat insects, especially bees, wasps and ants. This is the first time I have managed to photograph one with a bee in its mouth.
Green Bree-Eater with a bee in its beak.
Green Bee-Eater at Raga Svara
Coppersmith Barbet The coppersmith barbet (Psilopogon haemacephalus), also called crimson-breasted barbet and coppersmith, is an Asian barbet with crimson forehead and throat, known for its metronomic call that sounds similar to a coppersmith striking metal with a hammer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanctuary at Raga</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/sanctuary-at-raga/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/sanctuary-at-raga/</guid>
      <description>Raga is a sanctuary amidst swathes of dry, arid expanse. It is incredible, almost magical, to see what a small parcel of land, taken care of, loved, can do for our ecology. The primary dwellers of Raga are the trees, plants, birds and animals. Our ecology is kind and strong, caring and wanton in equal measure.
In early winter mornings at Raga, I find a solace that is rare, nearly impossible to feel in the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northstar Campus Walk - November 2022</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/campus_nov2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/campus_nov2022/</guid>
      <description>Walking around The Northstar School is meditation for me. Some images from today&amp;rsquo;s walk.
Kassod We have a few Kassod trees (Senna siamea) on the campus near the swimming pool. They are quite large now, 6 years old). To a layman, it can be easily confused with Copperpos tree, which are also present on the campus. They both have similar looking yellow flowering. Kassod flowers twice a year, once after rain till December and again in summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Khijadiya Bird Sanctuary</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/khijadiya_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/khijadiya_2022/</guid>
      <description>On 30th October 2022, I visited Khijadiya Bird Sanctuary. This was my second visit. Its about 70 kms from Rajkot. One of my favorite things is to be in forests and jungles. Khijadiya has great diversity of native and migratory birds. Since October is just the onset of winter, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to see more migratory birds. My camera does not have a long zoom range (230mm on crop sensor), so I am unable to give justice to these majestic birds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Buck National Park</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/velavadar_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/velavadar_2022/</guid>
      <description>I visited the Black Buck National Park in Velvadar (Bhavnagar) on 28th October 2022. This was my first trip to this park. It is protected area names after Black Bucks.
Landscape The landscape is a gorgeous swathe of copper-gold grasses.
Landscape of Black Buck National Park
Grasslands of Velavadar
Black Buck Males are black coloured with spiraling horns. A male black buck with shiny black coat
A galloping female black buck</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
