<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>readings on Mohit Khodidas</title>
    <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/readings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in readings on Mohit Khodidas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2019, Steve Francia and Mohit Patel; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/readings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Turn of the Screw</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/turn_of_the_screw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/turn_of_the_screw/</guid>
      <description>I just completed Turn of the Screw by Henry James. Horrifying in some parts and labrouious to read in most parts. The sentences and sytax is very Henry James-like. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I was Introduced to Borges</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/how_i_was_introduced_to_borges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/how_i_was_introduced_to_borges/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I wonder how I stumbled upon Borges. I remember one passage that shattered my mind. The opening paragraph of Michel Foucault&amp;rsquo;s The Order of Things had these lines:
This book first arose out of a passage in Borges, out of the laughter that shattered, as I read the passage, all the familiar landmarks of my thought - our thought, the thought that bears the stamp of our age and our geography - breaking up all the ordered surfaces and all the planes with which we are accustomed to tame the wild profusion of existing things, and continuing long afterwards to disturb and threaten with collapse our age-old distinction between the Same and the Other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning Roberto Bolaño</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/beginning_roberto_bolano/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/beginning_roberto_bolano/</guid>
      <description>The greatest writer of the 20th century, if not all time, for me, is Jorge Luis Borges. And if one reads Borges, he must also read Roberto Bolaño. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read Bolaño before and I am starting with 2666. A serendipitous start with this quote in the book&amp;rsquo;s opening:
An oasis of horror in a desert of boredom. -Charles Baudelaire
And Baudelaire reminds me that I must return to Fleurs du Mal soon again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ones Who Walk Away From Omelas</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/ones_who_walk_away_omelas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/ones_who_walk_away_omelas/</guid>
      <description>We will be reading a short story by Ursula Le Guin. She is one of the greatest Scifi writers (and one of my favourites). This short story, The Ones Who Walk Away From Omelas, presents a moral dilemma.
Ursula Le Guin shows a city; full of happy people; people without bondage and guilt; dancing in carnivals under bright, clear skies. Their perfect lives have just one condition: a single child tortured indefinitely.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
