<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Mohit Khodidas</title>
    <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Mohit Khodidas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2019, Steve Francia and Mohit Patel; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Khijadiya Bird Sanctuary</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/khijadiya_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/khijadiya_2022/</guid>
      <description>On 30th October 2022, I visited Khijadiya Bird Sanctuary. This was my second visit. Its about 70 kms from Rajkot. One of my favorite things to do is be in forests and jungles. Khijadiya has great diversity of native and migratory birds. October is just the onset of winter, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to see more migratory birds. My camera does not have a long zoom range (230mm on crop sensor) so I am unable to give justice to these majestic birds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Does it Mean to be a Teacher?</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/what_does_it_mean_to_be_a_teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/what_does_it_mean_to_be_a_teacher/</guid>
      <description>Happy Teachers&amp;rsquo; Day to all teachers.
Hermann Hesse said, &amp;ldquo;Teachers are more essential than anything else, men and women who can give the young the ability to judge and distinguish, who serve them as examples of the honouring of truth, obedience to the things of the spirit&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
Teachers and administrators (us) are essentially humans. We are people before we are teachers. And the failings and travails of being human cannot be discarded in the process of becoming a teacher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussion on Philosophy of Wildlife Conservation</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/philosophy_wildlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/philosophy_wildlife/</guid>
      <description>I look forward to Fridays each week. Fridays are for Noesis, our philosophy class. Over the years I have veered more and more towards literature and philosophy embedded in literature. But sometimes, we take up something topical and dive deep in to it. 29th July, Friday was International Tiger Day. I thought it would be a good opportunity to discuss about the philosophy of wildlife conservation.
I am deeply moved by the jungles of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My House will have a Roof</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/my_house_will_have_a_roof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/my_house_will_have_a_roof/</guid>
      <description>Anahata at Raga Svara
It is easy to believe that Raga Svara is a &amp;ldquo;business&amp;rdquo; and that it is different from Northstar or RKU, which are our learning institutions. But that would be an error. If anything, Raga is an even more potent form of learning. Raga is about bringing back the prime mover of transformation within one&amp;rsquo;s self, which so often is not the case in formal learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loathsome</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/loathsome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/loathsome/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you are in a thick forest. The old trees stand guard. The winding river gently invites you deeper. A half-penetrable mist settles over the water. No sound. No birds. Just the gentle trickle of water dropping from the oars. A maddening shriek tears the sky. A primeval scream. Silence. The old trees stand guard against vainglorious usurpers. The river flows. The oars push ahead. A heart of darkness.
Make of it what you will&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Own Garden</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/our_own_garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/our_own_garden/</guid>
      <description>Our garden has been barren for many months now. The kids, who tend to this garden, are living strange lives in their own homes; disconnected from each other and from us. This Teachers&amp;rsquo; Day we brought it alive again. It has been two years since we started the horticulture program. As I reflected on why we started this and what it means, I was reminded of Candide by Voltaire.
Travelling through Europe and witnessing poverty, destitution, destruction, corruption and the wickedness of the human soul, Candide and his friends, Professor Pangloss and Martin, arrive in the Ottoman Turkey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money - The Poe Way</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/money_poe_way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/money_poe_way/</guid>
      <description>While reading Poe today morning, came across this little gem on making money.
Epigram for Wall Street by Edgar Allan Poe
I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you a plan for gaining wealth, Better than banking, trade or leases,
Take a bank note and fold it up,
And then you will find your money in creases!
This wonderful plan, without danger or loss,
Keeps your cash in your hands, where nothing can trouble it;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Hospitality</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/thoughts_on_hospitality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/thoughts_on_hospitality/</guid>
      <description>With Raga Svara, and with Northstar as well, but more acutely at Raga, I come to the question of étranger or xenos. I am unable to take on the role of a subservient host. Hospitality is an act of giving and receiving, a game if you will. The rules and codes must be adhered to. However, it always remains a struggle. It never is a transaction.
While all our services are priced, value truly remains outside of economic rationality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Triangulum Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/triangulum_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/triangulum_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>Triangulum Galaxy
This is the Triangulum Galaxy. It is a spiral galaxy 2.73 million light-years from Earth in the constellation Triangulum. It is one of the most distant permanent objects that can be viewed with the naked eye. However, it is impossible to see it in any city or small town. There needs to be almost zero light pollution to see it. Even with 150 images stacked together, my image (above) shows a faint galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orion Nebula</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/orion_nebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/orion_nebula/</guid>
      <description>Orion Nebula (M42)
Fire in the sky. Orion Nebula.
My third attempt at this deep sky object. I took over 150 images of 30 seconds each and stacked them together to get a final image. The light pollution is making it more and more difficult to do any night sky observing. The universe is up there to see only if we could be mindful about artificial lights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turn of the Screw</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/turn_of_the_screw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/turn_of_the_screw/</guid>
      <description>I just completed Turn of the Screw by Henry James. Horrifying in some parts and labrouious to read in most parts. The sentences and sytax is very Henry James-like. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Cluster in Pegasus</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/star_cluster_in_pegasus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/star_cluster_in_pegasus/</guid>
      <description>The central star cluster in this photo is the Globular Cluster in constellation Pegasus. This is my second cluster photo after [[Hercules Globular Cluster]] I have been able to do a better job at the capturing the incredible star density. I do not wish to make technical observations. These photographs are meant to create a poetic image. It has no past and no future. Just an emergence in a reader&amp;rsquo;s psyche.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vega</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/vega/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/vega/</guid>
      <description>I love photographing solitary stars. I love the simplicity of the composition. This is Vega. It is a bright star (brihgtest in the constellation Lyra). Vega used to be Earth&amp;rsquo;s pole star around 12000 BC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Walk in the Campus</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/a_walk_in_the_campus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/a_walk_in_the_campus/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks back I shared some images of the Agave Americana entering its flowering season. Here are some updates.
Ketaki (Agave americana) Kadamb (Neolamarckia cadamba) And look at these majestic flowers of Kadamb (Neolamarckia cadamba). The large woolly balls are its flowers packed together in this shape. The organe colour looks captivating when it catches the sunlight. Saptaparni (Alstonia scholaris) Saptaparnis line the entrance avenue at Northstar. They are still young but already about 20 feet tall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andromeda Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/andromeda_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/andromeda_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>This is Andromeda Galaxy. Photographing this one was really hard for me. Many many hours to get this image. Astronomy and astrophotography is a humbling experience. What we are seeing is 2.5 million light years away. And it is still the closest galaxy to ours. This imageAndromeda contains more than 1 trillion stars. I still have a long way to go to improve my astro work but I&amp;rsquo;m proud of this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I was Introduced to Borges</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/how_i_was_introduced_to_borges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/how_i_was_introduced_to_borges/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I wonder how I stumbled upon Borges. I remember one passage that shattered my mind. The opening paragraph of Michel Foucault&amp;rsquo;s The Order of Things had these lines:
This book first arose out of a passage in Borges, out of the laughter that shattered, as I read the passage, all the familiar landmarks of my thought - our thought, the thought that bears the stamp of our age and our geography - breaking up all the ordered surfaces and all the planes with which we are accustomed to tame the wild profusion of existing things, and continuing long afterwards to disturb and threaten with collapse our age-old distinction between the Same and the Other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Babylon Lottery</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/babylon_lottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/babylon_lottery/</guid>
      <description>This week I led a close reading of Jorge Luis Borges&amp;rsquo;s short story The Babylon Lottery. It is one of my favourite short stories.
Babylon Lottery</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indian Higher Education and Rankings</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/indian_higher_education_and_rankings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/indian_higher_education_and_rankings/</guid>
      <description>/Posted originally at projectnoesis.in on [2021-03-08]/
Let&amp;rsquo;s acknowledge the problem, so we can get working
A couple of years ago I wrote in a dejected Facebook post that I spend more of my time in authority appeasement then on creative work. While I have learned to refrain from making caustic remarks, what remains true is that the fundamental nature of relationship between private Higher Education Institutions (HEIs) and departments is one of distrust and whataboutery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emil Cioran and the Impossibility of Meaning</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/emil_cioran_and_the_impossibility_of_meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/emil_cioran_and_the_impossibility_of_meaning/</guid>
      <description>And so I begin my dive in to Emil Cioran. I have never been optimistic about anything in my life. And Cioran resonates with me like very few others have. Just leaving some aphorisms below. May be someday I will write more about it. But really, would there be any point to that?
It is not worth the bother of killing yourself, since you always kill yourself too late.
What do you do from morning to night?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranks and Rankers</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/ranks_and_rankers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/ranks_and_rankers/</guid>
      <description>In all matters of taste and rankings and classifications that we inadvertently take part in our daily lives, I go back to Bourdieu and his thoughts on distinction:
Taste classifies, and it classifies the classifier. Social subjects, classified by their classifications, distinguish themselves by the distinctions they make, between the beautiful and the ugly, the distinguished and the vulgar, in which their position in the objective classifications is expressed or betrayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem of Evil</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/problem_of_evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/problem_of_evil/</guid>
      <description>We had session on the Problem of Evil. A very basic reading to start would be this. I aslo recommend reading two chapter from Fyodor Dostevsky&amp;rsquo;s The Brothers Karamazov: The Rebellion and The Grand Inquisitor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning Roberto Bolaño</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/beginning_roberto_bolano/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/beginning_roberto_bolano/</guid>
      <description>The greatest writer of the 20th century, if not all time, for me, is Jorge Luis Borges. And if one reads Borges, he must also read Roberto Bolaño. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read Bolaño before and I am starting with 2666. A serendipitous start with this quote in the book&amp;rsquo;s opening:
An oasis of horror in a desert of boredom. -Charles Baudelaire
And Baudelaire reminds me that I must return to Fleurs du Mal soon again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Teachers&#39; Day</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/happy_teachers_day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/happy_teachers_day/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this sometime back. Resharing on the occasion of Teachers&amp;rsquo; Day in India.
What, then, is truth? A mobile army of metaphors, metonyms, and anthropomorphisms – in short, a sum of human relations, which have been enhanced, transposed, and embellished poetically and rhetorically, and which after long use seem firm, canonical, and obligatory to a people: truths are illusions about which one has forgotten that this is what they are; metaphors which are worn out and without sensuous power; coins which have lost their pictures and now matter only as metal, no longer as coins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lutheran Insulter</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/lutheran_insulter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/lutheran_insulter/</guid>
      <description>Fabulous! Go here for some exquisite insults. Lutheran Insulter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes on Education</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/quotes_on_education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/quotes_on_education/</guid>
      <description>Richard Rorty Rorty presents knowledge, not as a representation of the real world or a “match” between knowledge and reality, but rather as a collection of conceptual structures that are adapted, or viable, within a person&amp;rsquo;s range of experience. In other words, the person&amp;rsquo;s knowledge “fits” with the world, much like how a key fits a lock (Bodner, 1986). Each of us builds our own key by making sense of the world, and many different keys can open a given lock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Afghanistan: A Story in Images</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/afghanistan_images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/afghanistan_images/</guid>
      <description>We are witnessing a crisis unfold in our time. I grew up in the 90s and remember the night of September 11, 2001. Disbelief, disorientation. I was too young to understand what led to it and what followed. I will be exploring the beautiful, tragic, complex and tumultuous past and present of Afghanistan through images. I am no expert in Afghan history or IR or geopolitics. We will only look at images and wonder about the reasons and costs of war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking about Thinking</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/thinking_about_thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/thinking_about_thinking/</guid>
      <description>As an educator, one of the key ideas that I explore is thinking. One of the goals to start Noesis, my philosophy class at The Northstar School, was to learn and teach the process of thinking with students and educators. I used to say that learning the process of thinking is an extremely important skill. I still believe that. My primary influence in this regard has been John Dewey. In his book How We Think, he writes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Walk in the Northstar Campus</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/a_walk_in_northstar_campus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/a_walk_in_northstar_campus/</guid>
      <description>New leaves in this young Kassod on the campus. We are in peak monsoon right now. It normally flowers after monsoon until December. The flowers are yellow and look quite pretty in bunches.
The canopy is not quite shapely yet. It&amp;#39;s still young.
This is Agave Americana and it has started flowering. The central spike is about 4 ft right now but it will go much much higher. It will flower in the most incredible way which is difficult describe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ones Who Walk Away From Omelas</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/ones_who_walk_away_omelas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/ones_who_walk_away_omelas/</guid>
      <description>We will be reading a short story by Ursula Le Guin. She is one of the greatest Scifi writers (and one of my favourites). This short story, The Ones Who Walk Away From Omelas, presents a moral dilemma.
Ursula Le Guin shows a city; full of happy people; people without bondage and guilt; dancing in carnivals under bright, clear skies. Their perfect lives have just one condition: a single child tortured indefinitely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raga Svara Habitat Collective</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/habitat_collective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/habitat_collective/</guid>
      <description>Aristotle said something to the effect that nature has made all things specifically for the sake of man and that the value of non-human thing in nature is merely instrumental. This line of thinking troubles me. And, it continues till this day. The inherent drive for dominion of man over nature. It is not just Aristotle, although he seems to be foremost in a long line of similar thought. Genesis 1: 27–8 states: And God blessed them, and God said unto them, Be fruitful, and multiply, and replenish the earth, and subdue it: and have dominion over fish of the sea, and over fowl of the air, and over every living thing that moveth upon the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Schools</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_schools/</guid>
      <description>What, then, is truth? A mobile army of metaphors, metonyms, and anthropomorphisms – in short, a sum of human relations, which have been enhanced, transposed, and embellished poetically and rhetorically, and which after long use seem firm, canonical, and obligatory to a people: truths are illusions about which one has forgotten that this is what they are; metaphors which are worn out and without sensuous power; coins which have lost their pictures and now matter only as metal, no longer as coins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Method</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_method/</guid>
      <description>कबीरा कुआँ एक है,
पानी भरे अनेक
भांडे ही में भेद है,
पानी सब में एक
-Kabir
O Kabir, there is but one well
And many who draw
Difference is the vessel
Water stays the same.
(my poor translation)
Hermann Hesse, like Kabir, is one of those writers who can convey deep ideas with incredibly lucid writing. The Glass Bead Game is an exploration of many ideas. I was piqued by one on method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porosity of Boundaries</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/porosity_of_boundaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/porosity_of_boundaries/</guid>
      <description>One major objective for Raga Svara is to create, what I call, “Porosity of Boundaries”. I want to make the solid walls between apparently different ideas more porous, more accommodating. One such boundary is between western medicine and our traditional medicine. I have thought for quite sometime about Indian traditional systems, whether therapeutic or belief systems (many times they merge seamlessly) and their place in Raga Svara.
Ayurveda (perhaps the most popular among our traditional medicine systems) is loved and trusted by many.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tambourine Man</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/tambourine_man/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/tambourine_man/</guid>
      <description>Today, 25th May, is Bob Dylan&amp;rsquo;s birthday. Remembering days from the past and how Dylan got entangled in my memories.
I had never been on a road trip with friends. It was December of 2007. We were going from Cambridge to Motherwell, near Glasgow. It was not a vacation trip. We were going for an on-site project. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t travelled much in the UK. We were in Cambridge University&amp;rsquo;s van. I didn&amp;rsquo;t drive since I had no license and no confidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sirius</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/sirius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/sirius/</guid>
      <description>With the incredibly light polluted city of Rajkot, I continue to fail at getting any sort of deep sky objects. More than 50% moon brightness added to my misery. Even with new moon, I barely manage to see anything below 35 degree altitude. Light pollution is the least talked about perhaps. The maddening LED hoardings blinding the eye at signals, uplighters on buildings, random spotlights during events, and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Love of Monospace Fonts</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_the_love_monospace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_the_love_monospace/</guid>
      <description>I think good fonts can elevate a design and bad fonts do the opposite. As a reader my most intimate relationship is with print. The curves, the spacing, serif or sans, everything comes together to create a character of the graphemes. Over the years I have liked (and then stopped linking) many fonts. I&amp;rsquo;m listing some of my current favourites.
Proportional Fonts This is the type of font that you would see most often (almost always).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hercules Globular Cluster</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/hercules_globular_cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/hercules_globular_cluster/</guid>
      <description>So I had stopped photographing the skies for some months. I was not getting to a point of clicking any photos, let alone getting good ones. I simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t set up the gear properly. Astrophotography is highly technical requiring complex and sensitive equipment and some very quaint softwares which seem like they were made in late 90s. For every imaging session, it takes me about an hour of setup time. It takes me another 2 hours or for image capture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orion Nebula - First Target</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/orion_nebula_first/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/orion_nebula_first/</guid>
      <description>I have been wanting to combine my interests in astronomy and photography by exploring deep sky imaging. I have spent many hours getting this first image of Orion Nebula. This is a diffuse nebula in the Orion constellation. It is about 1500 light years away. About 700 new stars are being formed in the gases of this nebula. How incredible that I can see this nursery of stars from our planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pleiades</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/pleiades/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/pleiades/</guid>
      <description>Our lives are illuminated; sparsely, dimly. Just like pin points of starlight in the maddening blackness of the universe. Sometimes on a winter&amp;rsquo;s night, it can be achingly beautiful.
The Seven Sisters, or the Pleiades, is an open star cluster in Taurus. Known as Parvin in Urdu and Krittika in Hindi, these are hot blue luminous stars embedded in a hazy reflection nebula. Mostly 7 stars are visible to the naked eye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finitude</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/finitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/finitude/</guid>
      <description>As we go through the greatest humanitarian crisis of modern times, it is hard to maintain a semblance of sanity. So much suffering, so much pain all around. What can words do to those who have lost the ones they love? All the pent-up anger and pain, where will it unleash?
It feels like I am in some sort of waking sleep. So many people, including my relatives have passed away.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
