<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>astrophotography on Mohit Khodidas</title>
    <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/astrophotography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in astrophotography on Mohit Khodidas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2019, Steve Francia and the Mohit Patel; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/astrophotography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Triangulum Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/triangulum_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/triangulum_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>This is the Triangulum Galaxy. It is a spiral galaxy 2.73 million light-years from Earth in the constellation Triangulum. It is one of the most distant permanent objects that can be viewed with the naked eye. However, it is impossible to see it in any city or small town. There needs to be almost zero light pollution to see it. Even with 150 images stacked together, my image (above) shows a faint galaxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orion Nebula</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/orion_nebula/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/orion_nebula/</guid>
      <description>Orion Nebula (M42)
Fire in the sky. Orion Nebula.
My third attempt at this deep sky object. I took over 150 images of 30 seconds each and stacked them together to get a final image. The light pollution is making it more and more difficult to do any night sky observing. The universe is up there to see only if we could be mindful about artificial lights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Cluster in Pegasus</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/star_cluster_in_pegasus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/star_cluster_in_pegasus/</guid>
      <description>The central star cluster in this photo is the Globular Cluster in constellation Pegasus. This is my second cluster photo after [[Hercules Globular Cluster]] I have been able to do a better job at the capturing the incredible star density. I do not wish to make technical observations. These photographs are meant to create a poetic image. It has no past and no future. Just an emergence in a reader&amp;rsquo;s psyche.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vega</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/vega/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/vega/</guid>
      <description>I love photographing solitary stars. I love the simplicity of the composition. This is Vega. It is a bright star (brihgtest in the constellation Lyra). Vega used to be Earth&amp;rsquo;s pole star around 12000 BC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andromeda Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/andromeda_galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/andromeda_galaxy/</guid>
      <description>This is Andromeda Galaxy. Photographing this one was really hard for me. Many many hours to get this image. Astronomy and astrophotography is a humbling experience. What we are seeing is 2.5 million light years away. And it is still the closest galaxy to ours. This imageAndromeda contains more than 1 trillion stars. I still have a long way to go to improve my astro work but I&amp;rsquo;m proud of this one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
