<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>northstar on Mohit Khodidas</title>
    <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/northstar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in northstar on Mohit Khodidas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/northstar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Revamping K12 Education Methodology</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/revamping_k12_education/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/revamping_k12_education/</guid>
      <description>It would be unnecessary to overstate the prevalence of mental health challenges faced by teenagers and adolescents in the present world. It would suffice to reflect on one&amp;rsquo;s self and surroundings to see the prevalence of mental health disorders in our society. WHO states that one in seven 10 to 19-year-olds experiences a mental disorder, which remain largely unrecognized and untreated. Mental health conditions have cascading effects such as physical ailments, educational difficulties, social exclusion, and discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Realm Beyond Time and Conflict</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/realm_beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/realm_beyond/</guid>
      <description>To each child, school is a concept, a memory that is always felt, like a spectre of foggy remembrance, but seldom analysed. Schools and childhood collide and intersect; the two being our primal sources of future selves. A good, sustaining space, our school, must retain that character of gossamer, always connected but never pulling. At Northstar I try to build and preserve this nebulosity of memory and presence. As Stanislaw Lem said, &amp;ldquo;The ossified order of maturity destroys the primal richness of childhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concept of Man - Zaidi</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/concept_of_man.md/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/concept_of_man.md/</guid>
      <description>In 2002, I was ravelling to one of my favourite places in India - Shimla. Viceregal Lodge in Shimla is a beautiful building, housing the Indian Institute of Advanced Study. There is a small book store in the campus. While rummaging to antiquated books, I chanced upon Education and Humanism by Sabira K. Zaidi. I had never heard of her, and probably most have not. I bought the only copy available, clearly in disuse and disrepair, pages smelling of the decaying yellow-tinted paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhythm of Learning, Rhythm of Life</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/rhythm_of_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/rhythm_of_learning/</guid>
      <description>Ist mir mîn leben getroumet, oder ist es war? Have I dreamt my life, or was it a true one?
-Walther von der Vogelweide
Rhythm of Learning, Rhythm of Life.
Why did I write this for Northstar? More often than not, my thoughts are not teased out of the ball of wire mesh that they are. The first stirring of the poetic thought is perhaps uniquely undeterred, unmeshed. Some readers of poetry would say that the first reading is too timid, too unsure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northstar Campus Walk - November 2022</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/campus_nov2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/campus_nov2022/</guid>
      <description>Walking around The Northstar School is meditation for me. Some images from today&amp;rsquo;s walk.
Kassod We have a few Kassod trees (Senna siamea) on the campus near the swimming pool. They are quite large now, 6 years old). To a layman, it can be easily confused with Copperpos tree, which are also present on the campus. They both have similar looking yellow flowering. Kassod flowers twice a year, once after rain till December and again in summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northstar Campus Walk - November 2022</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/campus_nov2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/campus_nov2022/</guid>
      <description>Walking around The Northstar School is meditation for me. Some images from today&amp;rsquo;s walk.
Kassod We have a few Kassod trees (Senna siamea) on the campus near the swimming pool. They are quite large now, 6 years old). To a layman, it can be easily confused with Copperpos tree, which are also present on the campus. They both have similar looking yellow flowering. Kassod flowers twice a year, once after rain till December and again in summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Walk in the Campus</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/a_walk_in_the_campus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/a_walk_in_the_campus/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks back I shared some images of the Agave Americana entering its flowering season. Here are some updates.
Ketaki (Agave americana) Kadamb (Neolamarckia cadamba) And look at these majestic flowers of Kadamb (Neolamarckia cadamba). The large woolly balls are its flowers packed together in this shape. The organe colour looks captivating when it catches the sunlight. Saptaparni (Alstonia scholaris) Saptaparnis line the entrance avenue at Northstar. They are still young but already about 20 feet tall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Walk in the Northstar Campus</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/a_walk_in_northstar_campus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/a_walk_in_northstar_campus/</guid>
      <description>New leaves in this young Kassod on the campus. We are in peak monsoon right now. It normally flowers after monsoon until December. The flowers are yellow and look quite pretty in bunches.
The canopy is not quite shapely yet. It&amp;#39;s still young.
This is Agave Americana and it has started flowering. The central spike is about 4 ft right now but it will go much much higher. It will flower in the most incredible way which is difficult describe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Schools</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_schools/</guid>
      <description>What, then, is truth? A mobile army of metaphors, metonyms, and anthropomorphisms – in short, a sum of human relations, which have been enhanced, transposed, and embellished poetically and rhetorically, and which after long use seem firm, canonical, and obligatory to a people: truths are illusions about which one has forgotten that this is what they are; metaphors which are worn out and without sensuous power; coins which have lost their pictures and now matter only as metal, no longer as coins.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
