<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on Mohit Khodidas</title>
    <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on Mohit Khodidas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2019, Steve Francia and the Mohit Patel; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Discussion on Philosophy of Wildlife Conservation</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/philosophy_wildlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/philosophy_wildlife/</guid>
      <description>I look forward to Fridays each week. Fridays are for Noesis, our philosophy class. Over the years I have veered more and more towards literature and philosophy embedded in literature. But sometimes, we take up something topical and dive deep in to it. 29th July, Friday was International Tiger Day. I thought it would be a good opportunity to discuss about the philosophy of wildlife conservation.
I am deeply moved by the jungles of India.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My House will have a Roof</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/my_house_will_have_a_roof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/my_house_will_have_a_roof/</guid>
      <description>Anahata at Raga Svara
It is easy to believe that Raga Svara is a &amp;ldquo;business&amp;rdquo; and that it is different from Northstar or RKU, which are our learning institutions. But that would be an error. If anything, Raga is an even more potent form of learning. Raga is about bringing back the prime mover of transformation within one&amp;rsquo;s self, which so often is not the case in formal learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emil Cioran and the Impossibility of Meaning</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/emil_cioran_and_the_impossibility_of_meaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/emil_cioran_and_the_impossibility_of_meaning/</guid>
      <description>And so I begin my dive in to Emil Cioran. I have never been optimistic about anything in my life. And Cioran resonates with me like very few others have. Just leaving some aphorisms below. May be someday I will write more about it. But really, would there be any point to that?
It is not worth the bother of killing yourself, since you always kill yourself too late.
What do you do from morning to night?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem of Evil</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/problem_of_evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/problem_of_evil/</guid>
      <description>We had session on the Problem of Evil. A very basic reading to start would be this. I aslo recommend reading two chapter from Fyodor Dostevsky&amp;rsquo;s The Brothers Karamazov: The Rebellion and The Grand Inquisitor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking about Thinking</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/thinking_about_thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/thinking_about_thinking/</guid>
      <description>As an educator, one of the key ideas that I explore is thinking. One of the goals to start Noesis, my philosophy class at The Northstar School, was to learn and teach the process of thinking with students and educators. I used to say that learning the process of thinking is an extremely important skill. I still believe that. My primary influence in this regard has been John Dewey. In his book How We Think, he writes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ones Who Walk Away From Omelas</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/ones_who_walk_away_omelas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/ones_who_walk_away_omelas/</guid>
      <description>We will be reading a short story by Ursula Le Guin. She is one of the greatest Scifi writers (and one of my favourites). This short story, The Ones Who Walk Away From Omelas, presents a moral dilemma.
Ursula Le Guin shows a city; full of happy people; people without bondage and guilt; dancing in carnivals under bright, clear skies. Their perfect lives have just one condition: a single child tortured indefinitely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Method</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/on_method/</guid>
      <description>कबीरा कुआँ एक है,
पानी भरे अनेक
भांडे ही में भेद है,
पानी सब में एक
-Kabir
O Kabir, there is but one well
And many who draw
Difference is the vessel
Water stays the same.
(my poor translation)
Hermann Hesse, like Kabir, is one of those writers who can convey deep ideas with incredibly lucid writing. The Glass Bead Game is an exploration of many ideas. I was piqued by one on method.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
