<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nature on Mohit Khodidas</title>
    <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/nature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nature on Mohit Khodidas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2008–2019, Steve Francia and Mohit Patel; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mohit-patel.github.io/tags/nature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Khijadiya Bird Sanctuary</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/khijadiya_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/khijadiya_2022/</guid>
      <description>On 30th October 2022, I visited Khijadiya Bird Sanctuary. This was my second visit. Its about 70 kms from Rajkot. One of my favorite things is to be in forests and jungles. Khijadiya has great diversity of native and migratory birds. Since October is just the onset of winter, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to see more migratory birds. My camera does not have a long zoom range (230mm on crop sensor), so I am unable to give justice to these majestic birds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Khijadiya Bird Sanctuary</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/khijadiya_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/khijadiya_2022/</guid>
      <description>On 30th October 2022, I visited Khijadiya Bird Sanctuary. This was my second visit. Its about 70 kms from Rajkot. One of my favorite things is to be in forests and jungles. Khijadiya has great diversity of native and migratory birds. Since October is just the onset of winter, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to see more migratory birds. My camera does not have a long zoom range (230mm on crop sensor) so I am unable to give justice to these majestic birds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Buck National Park</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/velavadar_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/gallery/velavadar_2022/</guid>
      <description>I visited the Black Buck National Park in Velvadar (Bhavnagar) on 28th October 2022. This was my first trip to this park. It is protected area names after Black Bucks.
Landscape The landscape is a gorgeous swathe of copper-gold grasses.
Landscape of Black Buck National Park
Grasslands of Velavadar
Black Buck Males are black coloured with spiraling horns. A male black buck with shiny black coat
A galloping female black buck</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Buck National Park</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/velavadar_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/velavadar_2022/</guid>
      <description>I visited the Black Buck National Park in Velavadar (Bhavnagar) on 28th October 2022. This was my first trip to this park. It is a protected area named after Black Bucks.
Landscape The landscape is a gorgeous swathe of copper-gold grasses.
Landscape of Black Buck National Park
Grasslands of Velavadar
Black Buck Males are black coloured with spiraling horns. A male black buck with shiny black coat
A galloping female black buck</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Walk in the Campus</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/a_walk_in_the_campus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/a_walk_in_the_campus/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks back I shared some images of the Agave Americana entering its flowering season. Here are some updates.
Ketaki (Agave americana) Kadamb (Neolamarckia cadamba) And look at these majestic flowers of Kadamb (Neolamarckia cadamba). The large woolly balls are its flowers packed together in this shape. The organe colour looks captivating when it catches the sunlight. Saptaparni (Alstonia scholaris) Saptaparnis line the entrance avenue at Northstar. They are still young but already about 20 feet tall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Walk in the Northstar Campus</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/a_walk_in_northstar_campus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/a_walk_in_northstar_campus/</guid>
      <description>New leaves in this young Kassod on the campus. We are in peak monsoon right now. It normally flowers after monsoon until December. The flowers are yellow and look quite pretty in bunches.
The canopy is not quite shapely yet. It&amp;#39;s still young.
This is Agave Americana and it has started flowering. The central spike is about 4 ft right now but it will go much much higher. It will flower in the most incredible way which is difficult describe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raga Svara Habitat Collective</title>
      <link>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/habitat_collective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mohit-patel.github.io/post/habitat_collective/</guid>
      <description>Aristotle said something to the effect that nature has made all things specifically for the sake of man and that the value of non-human thing in nature is merely instrumental. This line of thinking troubles me. And, it continues till this day. The inherent drive for dominion of man over nature. It is not just Aristotle, although he seems to be foremost in a long line of similar thought. Genesis 1: 27–8 states: And God blessed them, and God said unto them, Be fruitful, and multiply, and replenish the earth, and subdue it: and have dominion over fish of the sea, and over fowl of the air, and over every living thing that moveth upon the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
